Guide to the Jane LaTour Papers WAG.317
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Jane LaTour Papers
1978-2023
2001-2015
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
LaTour, Jane
WAG.317
16.67 Linear Feet in 32 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 4 oversized flat boxes, 4 folders in shared housing, and 1 VHS tape in a shared manuscript box
45.58 Megabytes in 98 digital files
1 videocassettes (vhs)
Jane LaTour (1946-2023) was a journalist, labor activist, and educator who lived in New York City. She wrote for various union publications including The Indypendent and Hard Hat News; collaborated with numerous organizations including the New York Labor History Association and the National Organization for Women (NOW); and wrote the book Sisters in the Brotherhoods: Working Women Organizing for Equality in New York City. The Jane LaTour Papers (1978-2023) consist of materials created and/or collected by LaTour in the course of writing Sisters in the Brotherhoods including her book proposal, correspondence, research files, and oral history interview transcripts. The collection also includes promotional materials and press related to LaTour's Sisters in the Brotherhoods book tour; copies of articles written by LaTour focused upon labor movements and women in non-traditional work roles; research materials related to the #MeToo movement and other topics of interest to LaTour; conference materials such as programs and speeches; as well as photographs and t-shirts.
Biographical Note
Jane LaTour (1946-2023) was a journalist, labor activist, and educator living in New York City. LaTour wrote for various union publications including The Indypendent and Hard Hat News; collaborated with numerous organizations including the New York Labor History Association and the National Organization for Women (NOW); and wrote the book Sisters in the Brotherhoods: Working Women Organizing for Equality in New York City.
LaTour first became involved in labor activism in the 1960s, leading protests in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and Edison, New Jersey. In 1975 she earned her Bachelor of Arts in history and in 1979 she earned her Master of Arts in labor studies from Rutgers University.
In 1977, she became an organizer for District 65, United Auto Workers (UAW) and the Coalition for Labor Union Women. In the 1980s, LaTour began to focus more closely on union reform, particularly around issues effecting women working in non-traditional male-dominated professions. In 1989, LaTour was appointed as the director for the Women's Project for the Association of Union Democracy and also spent several years working with the White Lung Association, a nonprofit focused on educating the public about the hazards of asbestos exposure in the workplace.
As an educator, LaTour was affiliated with the labor education program at Empire State College at Queen's College, Cornell University's School of Industrial and Labor Relations (ILR), and New York University's Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives. Throughout her career, she participated in numerous academic, labor union, and feminist conferences.
LaTour was a two-time winner of the Mary Heaton Vorse Award, a labor journalism award in New York City. She was also awarded the John Commenford Labor Education Award in 2012.
Scope and Contents
The Jane LaTour Papers (1978-2023) consist of materials created and/or collected by LaTour in the course of writing Sisters in the Brotherhoods: Working Women Organizing for Equality in New York City, which was published by Palgrave Macmillan in 2008. This monograph focuses upon the lives and experiences of 23 women working in traditionally male dominated jobs in New York City. The subjects of each chapter range from female firefighters, union officials, electricians, telecommunication employees, truck drivers, plumbers, and biomedical engineers. Materials related to the creation of Sisters in the Brotherhoods include proposals for her book; correspondence with interview subjects and LaTour's publisher; research files and notes focused on women in the labor movement and trade employment; and oral history interview transcripts.
The collection also contains documents related to LaTour's Sisters in the Brotherhoods book tour in the form of promotional materials such as book advertisements, tour flyers, book tour invitations, and pamphlets; book reviews and press related to her speaking engagements; transcripts of speeches given throughout her book tour; print and digital photographs; and correspondence with critics, her publishers, and supporters of the book. Together, these materials provide insight into how LaTour came to write this book, why the subject matter was important to her, and the amount of work she applied to producing this monograph, as well as promoting it.
Throughout her career, LaTour also attended conferences focused upon gender equality, women's labor organizations, and labor history. To this effect, the collection contains materials from conferences LaTour attended and include transcripts of her speeches and interviews; conference programs; print and digital photographs; and background information about the conferences' focus and the organizations represented.
The Jane LaTour Papers also includes copies of articles and lectures written by LaTour focused upon labor movements and women in non-traditional work roles; research materials related to the #MeToo movement and other topics of interest; correspondence between LaTour, friends, organizations she was affiliated with, and labor organizations; t-shirts from unions, non-profit organizations, and labor movements; and one VHS tape about female firefighter Brenda Berkman.
Recurring themes found across the Jane LaTour Papers include racial and sexual discrimination, gender equality, women in labor unions, vocational education, and pregnancy as it pertains to working women. These were all topics of importance to LaTour. Her extensive research and writings on these subjects; her numerous speaking engagements focused upon these subjects; and her active outreach within trades organizations, unions, and beyond – all of which is reflected in this collection – further establish her commitment towards gender equality and labor activism.
Arrangement
The collection has been arranged thematically starting with materials related to the writing of Sisters in the Brotherhoods, then the promotion of Sisters in the Brotherhoods, then materials from conferences Jane LaTour attended, and finally papers relating topics of interest and/or importance to LaTour and her original writings. Within these groupings, materials were arranged alphabetically by file title.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Jane LaTour in several installments between 2000-2016. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1950.189, 2011.012, 2016.036, NPA.2000.132, and 2019.119. Provenance unknown for materials found in the repository that were added to the collection in 2014. The accession number associated with these materials is 2014.060.
In August 2023, Gail Malmgreen donated materials collected following the death of Jane LaTour; the accession number for this gift is 2023.094.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Related Materials
New York Hard Hat News Records (WAG.212), White Lung Association: New York Chapter Records (WAG.077), Association for Union Democracy: Women's Project Records (WAG.331), United Automobile Workers of America District 65 Records (WAG.006),
Women -- Employment -- New York (State) -- New York; Women labor union members -- New York (N.Y.); Women labor leaders -- New York (State) -- New York; Sexual harassment of women; Sex discrimination in employment.; Sex discrimination against women.; Research notes.; Photographs.; Conferences.; Correspondence.; Essays.; New York (N.Y.).; T-shirts; Reproductive rights -- United States; Digital images.; LaTour, Jane; Berkman, Brenda
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Book Proposal, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Material -- Chapter 1: Rosie's Daughters, 1978-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Chapter 2: United Tradeswomen - Organizing for the Guaranteed Right to Work in Any Jobs, 1991-2005 (Box 1, Folder 3-5, Box 36, Folder 1, Box 37)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Chapter 4: When Worlds Collide - The First Women in Electrician's Local 3, 2001-2007 (Box 1, Folder 6-8, Box 36, Folder 2)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Chapter 5: Ticket to Ride, 1995-2007 (Box 1, Folder 9-10, Box 2, Folder 1-4, Box 36, Folder 3, Box 37, Folder 2)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Chapter 6: Sticking to the Union, 1990-2005 (Box 2, Folder 5, Box 37, Folder 3)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Chapter 7: Uncivil Service at the Board of Education, 1990-2007 (Box 2, Folder 6-10, Box 3, Folder 1, Box 36, Folder 4, Box 37)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Chapter 8: Double Vision - Breaking Down Doors at the FDNY, 1992-2008 (Box 3, Folder 2-7, Box 4, Box 36, Folder 5-6, Box 37, Folder 5)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Chapter 9: From Economic to Electronics - The Making of an Activist, 1994-2009 (Box 5, Folder 1-2, Box 37, Folder 8)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Chapter 10: That's Just the Way It Was - AT&T and the Struggle for Equal Opportunity, 1990-2007 (Box 5, Folder 3-7, Box 36, Folder 7, Box 37, Folder 9)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Chapter 11: Women on the Move, 1990-2007 (Box 6, Folder 1-2, Box 37, Folder 10)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Chapter 12: Against the Grain, 1978-2006 (Box 6, Folder 3-9, Box 37, Folder 11)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Chapter 13: Getting Past Pioneering, 1992-2008 (Box 7, Folder 1-3, Box 37, Folder 12)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Epilogue: Where Are They Now?, 2002-2007 (Box 7, Folder 3-7)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Barbara Trees, 1995-2004 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Discrimination, 2001-2006 (Box 36, Folder 11, Box 37, Folder 7)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Expert Allies to Interview, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- General, 2006 (Box 36, Folder 10)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Nancy MacLean, 2005-2007 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Sophia Smith Collection (Smith College), 1997-2005 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives (NYU), 1986-2002 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Research Materials -- Teamsters, 1994-2008 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods --Book Party at Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives (NYU), 2008 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Book Reviews, 2008-2012 (Box 9, Folder 2-8, Box 36, Folder 8)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Book Tour, 2009-2015; cuid42581 (Box 9, Folder 9-10, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12, Folder 1-8, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_WAG_317_ER_1)
  Scope and Contents
  Jane LaTour traveled across the United States promoting her book. Locations visited include: Washington, D.C.; Waltham, MA; Binghamton, NY; New York, NY; Potsdam, NY; Albany, NY; Dululth, MN; Cleveland, OH; Boston, MA; Highland Park, NJ; Indiana; Ithaca, NY; New Haven, CT; Ossining, NY; Rochester, NY; and Vermont.
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Campaign for Paperback Edition, 2008-2009 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Columbia University Oral History Workshop, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Correspondence, 2002-2017 (Box 13, Box 14, Folder 1-3)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- History News Network Independent Scholar Profile, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Interviews, 2009-2011 (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Labor Arts Exhibit, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Photographs by Gary Schoichet for Book, 2005-2009 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- Publicity & Promotional Materials, 2008-2016 (Box 14, Folder 9, Box 15, Box 36, Box 37, Folder 6)
- Sisters in the Brotherhoods -- SUNY Albany Oral History Project, 2009-2010 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Conferences -- 2010 Researching New York (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Conferences -- Assembly Roundtable on Women in Non-Traditional Occupations, 2001-2002 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Conferences -- Berkshires Conference on Women and History, 2013 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Conferences -- Freedom on Our Terms (Bella Abzug Leadership Institute), 2007 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Conferences -- Gotham History Festival, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Conferences -- How Class Works (SUNY Stonybrook), 2010 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Conferences -- Laborfest, 2010; cuid42582 (Box 16, Folder 8, Box 36, Folder 12, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_WAG_317_ER_3)
- Conferences -- Labor Notes, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Conferences -- National Organization for Women (NOW), 2001-2002 (Box 17, Folder 1, Box 36, Folder 14)
- Conferences -- New Left Forum, 2010-2012 (Box 17, Folder 2-4)
- Conferences -- New York City College of Technology, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Conferences -- North American Labor History Conference, 2002, 2008 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Conferences -- Northeast Regional Summer School for Union Women, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Conferences -- "Opportunity Downtown: Women Working" (Women and Construction Jobs), 2004 (Box 17, Folder 8, Box 36, Folder 13, Box 37)
- Conferences -- Price and Solidarity in Action, 2010 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Conferences -- Race, Labor, and the City: Crises Old and New (Labor and Working-Class History Association, LAWCHA), 2009 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Conferences -- Rethinking Marxism, 2009 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Conferences -- Sisters on the Front Line (Cornell University), 2007-2008 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Conferences -- Society of American Archivists (SAA), 2010-2011 (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
- Conferences -- Tales of Workplace Danger and Advocacy, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Conferences -- Tradeswomen Now and Tomorrow (TNT), 2010; cuid42583 (Box 19, Folder 2, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_WAG_317_ER_2)
- Conferences -- United Women Firefighter's 30th Anniversary, 2012 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Conferences -- Women Building California, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 4, Box Shared Tamiment 169, Folder 8)
- Conferences -- Women Committee and Political Action, 2014 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Conferences -- Women in Construction Work, 2010, 2013 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Conferences -- Women's Institute (C.W. Post), 2010 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Conferences -- A Woman's Place: Access, Visibility, and Making Change in the Workplace (NYU Municipal Archives), 2015 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Conferences -- Women in Trades, 1989-2009 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Conferences -- Women and Unions: Still the Most Difficult Revolution? (Alice Cook's 100th Birthday Conference at Cornell University), 2003 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Conference Lectures, 2008-2011 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- #MeToo Movement and Women in Non-Traditional Roles, 2017-2018 (Box 20, Folder 2-4)
- Association for Union Democracy Inc., 1990 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- "Bread and Roses in the New Economy" (Working USA: The Journal of Labor and Society), 2005 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- "Breaking Through the Concrete Ceiling" (Heidi E. Wagner), 2018 (Box 29, Folder 5)
- "The Changing Face of Labor 1983-2008" (Center for Economic and Policy Research), 2009 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Chicago Women in Trades (CWIT), 1995, 2000-2010 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Chinese Staff and Workers Association - NYU Campaign, 1997-1998 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW), undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
- "Contradicting Male Power and Privilege: Class, Race, and Gender Relations in the Building Trades" (Francine Moccio), 1992 (Box 29, Folder 6)
- Cornell University School of Industrial and Labor Relations (ILR), 2014-2015 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Cornell University School of Industrial and Labor Relations (ILR) -- "A Guide to Organizing Women's Committees", 2014-2015 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Correspondence -- General, 1991, 2009-2012 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Correspondence -- The General Society of Mechanics and Tradesmen, 2013 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Correspondence -- Hard Hatted Women, 2010-2014 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Correspondence -- New York City Taxi Driver Oral History Project, 2011 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Correspondence -- Personal, 2016-2018 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Correspondence -- Tradeswomen Advocates, 2003-2010 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Correspondence -- Women in Non-Traditional Jobs, 2009-2016 (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
- "Deconstructing Tradition" The Struggle and Progress of the Women Building New York City" (Kyle Friend), 2018 (Box 29, Folder 7)
- "Diverse Working Class Women in Skilled Trade Occupations: An Apprenticeship Model for Success" (Lynn Judith Shaw), 2001 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Domestic Violence, 1996-2007 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
- Draft of Miriam Frank's Cut in the Union, Chapter 2 "From Construction to Couture", 2002 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Elaine Ward vs. City of New York Department of Buildings, 2014; cuid42584 (Box 23, Folder 4, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_WAG_317_ER_4)
- Elinore Morehouse Herrick -- American National Biography Draft by Jane LaTour, 2014-2015 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Elinore Morehouse Herrick -- Correspondence (Jane LaTour and American National Biography), 2014-2015 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Elinore Morehouse Herrick -- Research Materials, 2014-2015 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Essay Review by Jane LaTour - "Overcoming Isolation on the Job", 2010 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Evan Ruderman, 2003, 2008 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Female Doormen, 2008 (Box 29, Folder 8)
- Female Miners and North Country, 2005-2007 (Box 23, Folder 10, Box 37, Folder 16)
- "From Breasts to Breasts" (Amy Gernon), 2008 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Gender Equality and Discrimination, 2007-2019 (Box 24, Folder 2-7, Box 25, Folder 1, Box 36, Folder 16-17, Box 37, Folder 15)
- Gender Relations in the Building Trade (Oral History Collection), 2008 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- "Gendered Terrain: Male and Female Space on the Automotive Shop Floor, 1920-1980" (Steve Meyer), 2005 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Hard Hat Magazine, 1997, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Her Own Words: Women in Non-Traditional Careers (Review of 11 videos), 2002-2005 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- "Hiding Behind Their Skirts" (Angela Olszewski), 2010 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Hillary Clinton, 2006-2008 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- "If I Had A Hammer" (Jane LaTour), 2012 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- The Indypendent, 2012 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- International Labor Organizations (ILO) -- Female Unions, 2007 (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Interview - Council of School Supervisors and Administrators (CSA) News, 2012 (Box 25, Folder 10)
- Lectures -- Alice Kessler-Harris and Nancy MacLean, 2005-2006 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Lectures -- Center for Workers Education, 2004 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Lectures -- Ethical Issues in the Workplace: Busting Barriers (Berkeley College), 2011 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Lectures -- Hofstra University, 2013 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Lectures -- New York Society for Ethical Cultures, 2013 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Legal Momentum - The Woman's Legal Defense and Education Fund, 2014 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- "Lessons of Affirmative Action for Women in the U.S. Highway Construction Industry" (Vivian Price, PhD), 1998 (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Local One International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employeess (IATSE), 2011-2013 (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Masculinities Under Construction: Gender, Class, and Race in a Man's Man's World (Kirsten Paap), 1999 (Box 26, Folder 9-10)
- Metro Detroit Skilled Tradewomen Oral History Project, 2005-2007 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- National Writers Union, 2011 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- New York Labor History Association, 1999, 2004-2005 (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Non-Traditional Employment for Women (NEW), 1991, 2004-2006 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Notebooks, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- Obituary and Memorial Ephemera, 2023 (Box Shared Tamiment 165, Folder 17)
- Operation Punch List (OPL), 2006-2008 (Box 27, Folder 6-7)
- Operation Punch List (OPL) -- Conference -- Women Rebuilding New York City, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 8)
- Operation Punch List (OPL) -- Project Pipeline, 2008-2009 (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Oral History Association, 2003 (Box 28, Folder 1)
- Oral History Project on Gender Relations in Non-Traditional Employment (Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Archives, NYU), 1990-2010 (Box 28, Folder 2-6)
- Original Poetry, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
- "Our Voice: A Participatory Action Research Project of SEIU Local 43413" (Teresa Lingafelter), 2003 (Box 28, Folder 8)
- Pay Equity, 2003-2009 (Box 28, Folder 9)
- Pay Equity -- Report on Gender Wages, 2004-2009 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Pride and Paycheck: Women's Guide to Blue Collar Jobs, 2003-2010 (Box 29, Folder 2)
- Poverty & Welfare, 2001-2008 (Box 30, Folder 2)
- Reproductive Rights, 2001-2006 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Roofers Local 8 Union, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 5)
- Subject File -- Betty Friedan, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 6, Box 36, Folder 15)
- Subject File -- Bianca Wisniewki, 2009-2010 (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
- Subject File -- Joi C. Beard, 2012 (Box 25, Folder 11)
- Subject File -- Judith Layzer, 2010-2011 (Box 25, Folder 12)
- Subject File -- Sue Cobble, 2002 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- Subject File -- Veronica Sessions, 2012 (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Subject File -- Walter Stafford, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- T-Shirts, undated, 1980, 1986 (Box 34, Box 35)
  The subjects of these t-shirts focus on unions, labor movements, and non-profit organizations that were important to LaTour. These t-shirts represent the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Union; the 1980 Transit Strike; The Challenge to Labor and Labor Education at New York Univeristy; Education without Exploitation Support Local 3882; Los Internacionales Unidos a los Espanoles, Luchamos Contra el Invasor; The Majority Coalition for a New NY; The New Teamsters Fighting for Good Jobs and a Better Future; White Lung Association; Women as Wage Earners; and District 65 United Automobile Workers (UAW).
- Taking the Heat: Brenda Berkman, 2006 (Box Shared Tamiment 172, Vhs 317.0001)
- Title IX, 2003-2010 (Box 31, Folder 6)
- Tradeswomen, 2005-2008 (Box 30, Folder 5)
- Tradeswomen Coffee House - Oral History Archives, 2005 (Box 31, Folder 7)
- Tradeswomen Now and Tomorrow (TNT), 2004-2006 (Box 31, Folder 8, Box 37, Folder 14)
- Tradeswomen Organizations, 2009-2010 (Box 31, Folder 9)
- Tradeswomen Surveys, 1997, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 1)
- Unions -- Photographs, 1997-1998, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Unions -- Stickers, undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
- United Electrical Workers Union, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
- Village Voice Article about Jane LaTour, 2010 (Box 32, Folder 6)